MATTHEW BURNS

Professional Summary:

Recent grad trying to gain exposure to the industry and build skillsets. I would like to learn more about full stack development and technologies. I also have an interest in security, and have some experience with application reverse engineering. In my first rotation at TDP, I gained experience with CI/CD pipelines and procedures, as well as software security remediation.

Location: AZ008 AZ - Phoenix

Technical Skills: (Novice, Intermediate, Advanced)

Programming Languages:

Java, C, Python, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, C#, Assembly/Machine Code, SQL, Groovy

Software:

Bash Shell Scripting, D3.js, Chrome DevTools, Splunk, Kafka, JUnit, VMware, Wordpress

Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Kali

Tools: Jenkins, Git, Fortify, Eclipse, Microsoft Office, GDB, Splunk **Other:**

Other:

<u>Communication</u>, Critical Thinking, Problem Solver, Scrum Framework, Team Skills, UX Design, DevOps

Professional Experience:

Optum, June 2020-Invalid Date Provided **SHIELD Team TDP Associate**

- Built a common CI/CD pipeline for 3 legacy java applications
- Remediated more than 250 Critical, High, and Medium Fortify security issues in multiple java applications
- Added security logging functionality into legacy applications and deployed them into production
- Worked within an Agile methodology to collaborate with Scrum team and meet sprint goals.

University of Arizona Computer Science Department, January 2020 - May 2020

Research Assistant

• Expanded the data collection capabilities of the Reverse Engineering Engine by completing reverse engineering challenges in IDA and Ghidra.

Visionary Ophthalmology, February 2014-July 2014 **Web Designer**

- Built 3 websites for the company using Wordpress and CSS.
- Maintained day-to-day technology needs including computer security and technical support

University of Arizona Computer Science Department, January 2013 - May 2013

Assistant

- Assisted in development of the Semantically Linked Instructional Content project site (www.slic.arizona.edu) by reviewing user-interface design to improve usability
- Ground-truthed presentation data to ensure accuracy in the SLIC training process and collaborated with a team of 5 to meet project needs

TerraPower, January 2008-July 2012 **Intern**

- Developed a frontend to reactor simulation application in Python.
- Created backend visualizations of simulation data using Python.
- Classified reactor components to create hierarchy diagrams based on technical specifications.
- Managed several records library transitions, including filing and organizing design documents during office relocations.

Education:

Bachelors - Computer Science - May 2020 University of Arizona